- Hey, folks, and welcome to the video
on "Finding and Using Design Inspiration."
So design inspiration for a beginner
might actually come as a
little bit of a surprise.
It is a shockingly important part
of improving your design craft.
Design inspiration just refers to
any nice designs that you see on the Web
or on a site like Dribbble or Behance
that designers post their work to.
And, in general, it's
just hugely important
to collect and catalog good
design inspiration as you see it
so that you can, one,
analyze it to get better,
but also, two, whenever you
have a specific design problem,
you then have good solutions
that you can go and reference,
and see if any of them
solve a similar problem.
So if I, say, don't know what font to use
in one particular app, I can go look at
all the inspiration I've
collected for similar apps
and get at least a couple
ideas or things to consider
for what to use as a font.
Now, this video's gonna
be divided into two parts.
In the first part, I'm
gonna talk mostly about
where to find good design inspiration.
And then in the second
part, I'm gonna talk about
what to do with it once you find it.
And I'm just gonna give you my sort of
low key ways of cataloging it,
although you are welcome to do
whatever system works best for you.
But the end goal is that
you never just click by
a good-looking site without
cataloging it in some way
or storing it, so that your
future self can refer to that
when you're stuck on a design issue.
All right, with that being
said, let's get started.
So I wanna start by drilling in
some of the importance
of design inspiration
and kind of giving you a
practical example of how it works.
If you've been watching
this course in order,
you've seen this design.
This is the very first design
that I designed professionally.
Someone paid me money to make this
and this design is just awful.
And, at the time, I mean,
it took me a ton of time.
It took me over 10 hours
to complete just this page.
I was trying as hard as I could.
And I was sort of frantically
looking at inspiration
for how to redesign this page.
And there's plenty of
things that I did wrong.
Like I used sort of this kind of
gross, pukey, yellow color up here,
and then there's sort of
this muddy brownish color
for a header.
I mean, even with just
with the colors alone
and all the mismatching, I have
this very bright, saturated,
red, green and blue here,
which doesn't really fit
with the general vibe
of anything else.
I could have looked at design inspiration
and seen very clearly
that people are rarely,
the best designs out there
are rarely going to use
something like a brown header.
Instead, they might use a gray header.
And this is something we'll talk about
just how important the color
gray is in the color unit.
We'll talk about all these
things in the color unit,
actually, about coming up with
matching palettes of colors,
about choosing more bright,
sort of richer colors
for your theme colors, for
things like buttons or whatever,
and then just the importance of gray.
And if you look here, I mean,
there's just a lot of kind of,
a large percentage of the screen is gray.
And if you count white as a shade of gray,
it's almost all of it.
And that was just not necessarily
something I understood.
I thought, oh, I need to kinda
fancy it up with textures.
And again, I didn't figure out
how all these colors fit together.
But the more design insp I looked at,
the more I realized, ah, okay,
this is sort of how things are done.
These are sort of the unwritten rules.
And those unwritten rules
I've written in this course,
but it was something that
took me a lotta time to notice
and a lot of studying the best designs,
and tryin' to kinda put together
the different patterns between them.
By the way, I did this redesign
of this page more recently,
and it took me 29 minutes.
So it was literally 20 times
quicker to do this design
than it was to do the original.
And obviously, this one
looks much, much better.
So this is a powerful
argument not only, I think,
for looking at design inspiration,
but also if you're at a
state where your designs
look more like this, don't
worry, we're gonna get here.
And all of the ideas in this
are covered in this course.
Everything from the
alignment, the spacing,
the data visualization,
there's a lesson on that,
it's all in here.
But I'm sort of getting ahead of myself.
The only thing I really wanna say is that
some of the critical ideas in here
about using, say, a gray for a header
or a very rich and bright theme color
rather than something
that's a dark yellow,
which is just to be avoided, or a brown,
which muddy brownish colors are
often to be avoided as well.
These are things that I had to look at
a lot of design inspiration
to realize, hmm,
I see the patterns here, I see
what pro designers are doing.
Now, the big question is,
where do you go to collect this
sort of design inspiration?
Probably the single best site
to collect design inspiration
is Dribbble.com, and that's
Dribbble with three b's.
Don't ask me the reason;
I don't understand it.
But it's a website where
designers post finished work
or sometimes works in progress.
And the idea is you can
follow different designers,
you can follow different design studios,
and you just get this stream
of incredible design inspiration.
And any of these that
I like, I can click in
and see a bigger version of the image
and maybe get a bit more information
about how they created this design.
I've got some recommendations
for who you could follow
on Dribbble posted below.
You can also go and check
out who I'm following.
And once you follow a sort
of a critical mass of people,
you're just gonna get this
constant stream of new ideas.
And what's really cool about Dribbble is
there is a invitation-only process.
So everyone who's posting here
has been invited to the site,
and that just keeps the
quality bar really high,
which is kinda nice.
There's not a lot of just
downright bad stuff on Dribbble.
Also, from an inspiration perspective,
one of my very favorite
things about Dribbble
is the fact that you can search by color.
So I can either enter
a hex color code here
or just like pick something.
So maybe I'll pick kind of
this bluish-indigo almost
sorta light color.
And I can go see what are some of the
best designers on earth doing
with this particular color?
And one question that I often answer
when I'm looking at Dribbble colors is,
what are they pairing it with?
So this sort of blue indigo,
I see a lotta yellow.
I see a lotta yellow coming up here
in some of these results.
And that might tell me that
if I know I have to use this
as the theme color, hey, why
don't I go and try yellow
as a secondary color?
Sorta similar to Dribbble
is this site called Behance.
Behance is cool.
I don't use it as much as
Dribbble, to be honest.
And one of the biggest reasons
is it's just not as
focused on digital work.
And I'm sure I could put in the effort
to follow people who
post just digital stuff,
but it does look like
there's various illustrations
or graphic design, or all
kinds of things going on here.
Not to say there aren't
great websites and apps here,
but I view this as kind of as
a secondary place to Dribbble,
which is more focused on digital design.
Now, Dribbble and Behance are nice
in that they make it easy to see
a large collection of good design.
But for the most part, these
are kind of like static images
or maybe quick little animations.
It's not really like being on a live site
or necessarily using a real app.
And so there's also some sort of,
I'm gonna call them screenshot sites,
but basically places where
they catalog screenshots
from real apps that have
actually been created,
and people can download
on their phones and use.
So one of the ones that I use plenty
is called Mobbin.Design.
I'm not really sure
what that means either.
We've got some weird names
in this design world.
But I can go and I can see, okay,
what is this version of Gmail look like?
And I can go check out a number
of screenshots from there.
Let's see if they're
gonna have other apps too,
if I just keep scrollin' down.
A lot of Gmail ones,
'cause they must have taken
all these screenshots very recently.
Anyhow, one thing you can do
is if you, say, filter by patterns,
I can look at all kinds
of particular filters
that might be useful here.
So if I'm making, say, a walk-through,
then I can go filter by
walk-throughs and just check out.
So here's EPSI, here's Masterclass,
here's Evernote, here's Zendesk.
And just with like one scroll
I've already seen four or
five professionally designed
apps walk-through processes.
Pttrns.com, that is with no vowels.
Again, the names, sheesh.
Pttrns.com also has a
number of iPhone apps.
I think they have Apple
Watch apps as well.
I'm not sure this is being
updated as frequently.
And some of these things kinda change,
the best sites to get screenshots.
It changes a little bit, new ones pop up
every once in awhile.
So I've actually got a bunch of
screenshot sites listed below.
And if you know any that
should be on that list,
feel free to email me at any point.
But the idea here is this is nice,
especially if you're
designing a mobile app
and you wanna see something that is real.
If you see some designs here,
you can either study them
on the site or you can
download them on your phone,
and then use them and get a
real feel for how they work.
And the last category I wanna talk about
for where to find good design inspiration
is just your normal Web browsing.
So I just landed on this site yesterday.
It's for Stripe's new Climate Initiative
and it's pretty cool.
It's a beautifully designed page,
as most Stripe pages are.
There's a lot goin' on here.
There's a lot I might study and like.
And the nice thing is if
I find design inspiration
that is a live site,
that's going to come with,
say, like the animations
that are part of this.
And so if you look, for instance,
this is a really cool animation,
as I slide between the different menus.
But that sort of stuff is not
necessarily easy to capture
in the static screenshots that
you usually see on Dribbble
or on something like Mobbin or Pttrns.
Another thing that's good
about collecting good sites
and just actually having
URLs that you can go to
where you know there's good design
is you can also see the
responsive design patterns.
So when I shrink this screen size down,
I can see exactly what's
gonna happen here.
That's not so with, say, just
some random Dribbble shot
that someone uploaded.
Finally, there is one other huge benefit
to finding and collecting live sites
as your design inspiration,
and that is that it's easy
to get the actual fonts.
So if you have WhatFont
installed, and you should,
you can just hover over
any font on the site
and see what font they're using.
So I might decide that,
hmm, I like this Stripe font quite a bit.
What is it?
Ah, it's Sohne-var,
which I'm gonna assume
means it's a variable font.
Okay, cool.
So for me, at least based
on my own experience,
those are the four biggest places
that I'm gonna get design
inspiration, Dribbble, Behance,
screenshot sites like Mobbin or Pttrns,
and then, of course, the
actual sites themselves.
Now, the big question that remains is,
what do you do once you have
found some design inspiration?
Well, it kinda depends
on where you found it.
There's a little bit of overlap here,
but let me just kind
of run through things.
If I find something
that I like on Dribbble,
one thing that's awesome about Dribbble
is it's very easy to store it
to what's called a collection.
So I can just click in here
and I can pick some collection.
These are all the ones that I have.
You can see I've got quite a bit
that I think it might belong to.
So let's say I do blue-purple
or something like that.
Oops, I need to create a new collection.
Blue-purple, create collection,
and boom, we're good to go.
Now, if I go into my own profile,
I can go to my collections
and then I can see all of this inspiration
that I have found over time.
And you can see it really
runs the gamut here.
I've got gradients that
only has this single shot.
I've got seven decks of cards that I like,
a couple brutalist design shots,
code editor shots, and so on.
It just sort of goes on and on.
This is absolutely a fantastic
feature that Dribbble has,
and I highly recommend
that you start putting
together collections.
Now, one problem with Dribbble collections
is they are all online,
so they're not necessarily available
if you happen to be offline.
And because of that,
I actually have some
shots that I just keep
in a good UI folder.
And a lot of these are from Dribbble,
some of them might be
screenshots of websites.
But the point is, I just wanna
have some amount of stuff
that I can go to
even if I don't happen
to have Internet access.
And so I just pressed command A,
and it looks like I have
182 items in this folder,
and you can see it's all kinds of stuff.
It's actually really cool.
But the whole idea here is,
I mean, it's even not digital stuff.
It's some book covers.
Yeah, there we go, there's
a bunch of book covers here,
a little animation, what have you.
But the whole idea is, if I'm ever working
and I don't have Internet access,
and I just need to see some random ideas
and kinda get those
creative juices flowing,
here's 182 things that
I have liked in the past
and might wanna look at now.
Of course, if you're on a
site like Mobbin or Pttrns,
then it makes a ton of sense
to save those images, too,
and kinda have that offline folder going.
Now, for the actual websites
that you want to bookmark,
I just keep it simple and
I actually do a bookmark.
So I have this folder right here
of bookmarks called Good UI.
And you can see I've got a bunch of these
listed in the course for ya,
but this is just some of the ones
that I most frequently reference.
You'll see these throughout the course.
And these are the ones
that I'm actually referencing
in my own design work.
This is just stuff that I've happened upon
that I really like.
And I believe Stripe is actually on here,
so I'm probably not gonna
add the Stripe Climate site,
but it's all good, and it's
just plenty of great stuff
that I can go get inspired by.
One thing that's
super-important to mention
about design inspiration
is this site right here,
Stripe's Climate Initiative site.
This might happen to be the sort of thing
that I want to design right now,
and so I'm gonna draw
inspiration directly from it.
But one of the most important
exercises you can do
as a beginning designer
is called copywork.
And copywork is where you
take a site that you like,
where you feel like you could
not design at that quality,
and then you copy that site as
an exercise pixel-for-pixel.
So I would just take a
screenshot of, say, this site
or a different site, I
would open it up in Figma,
and I would just recreate
it pixel-for-pixel.
I've actually done that fairly recently.
These aren't full sites, but you can see
these are just some of the things where
I saw this logo probably on
Dribbble and thought, geez,
I can't quite do that.
I wanna see if I can make
something that looks like that.
And it turns out I could.
And it's a great opportunity
to learn stuff about colors
and effects, and different
shapes and stuff like that.
Same thing with this.
You know, I didn't quite get here.
I need to do some shadows,
and some texture and stuff,
and a little bit of the lighting effects,
but okay, I'm gettin' there
as far as the shapes go.
That's pretty cool.
This one I haven't tried yet.
Recently, I saw this one, too.
And so you can see,
you know, I see this
awesome-looking 3D icon,
and this is just in Figma, I'm saying,
how can I recreate this pixel-for-pixel?
You see I didn't quite get it,
but I sure learned some interesting things
about lighting and about
textures as I was doing these.
Now, I'm doing these
small fancy little things
just because I've already
done a lotta copywork
on full sites, but that's
actually where I recommend
starting as a beginner.
So below, you're gonna find a link
to an article that I wrote
on Smashing Magazine.
They gave it this kind of obnoxious title,
but "Copy If You Can,
"Improving Your UI Design
Skills With Copywork."
I recommend that you go and read this
as part of the homework for this lesson.
Basically, I talk about
copying, here's one site,
this one I found on Dribbble,
copying as a way to learn.
And in particular, this is something that
writers and painters have
both been doing for centuries.
It's a little bit of a
newer idea for UI designers.
But just as, I think it was
Michelangelo recommended it
as one of the first exercises
that a beginning painter does,
this is definitely one of
the first things I recommend
a beginning designer does.
As you recreate a design,
so here's the original
and here's my recreation, you
learn all of these things.
Like, you can look at
this and not really notice
what are all the little
techniques and tactics
that went into this design.
But when you recreate
it for pixel-for-pixel,
you have to notice all those things.
And so I talk about how, for instance,
one thing I notice is, in this
abbreviation for Hawaii, HI,
this is actually like
size 360 or something.
And just before I'd seen this
design, I had never considered
that you would have
text be size 360, right?
But at some point, it gets large enough
where it's basically a visual element.
And that's not to say you wanna do this
in every design, right?
If this was like more than two letters,
that would get pretty absurd.
But the point is it works for this design
and it's sort of a strategy that,
now that I realize it's
something I can do,
I can bring it to other designs.
Likewise, one thing that's
really cool about this design,
this is Dann Petty's design
for the original Epicurrence Conference,
is he uses these sort of watercolor marks
as a design element all throughout.
Now you'll notice there's plenty of stuff
that I did in the copywork
where I didn't get it perfectly right
or I skipped, you know,
here's The Full Epic Crew.
Well, it's not The Full Epic Crew.
Turns out he has like 100
other names that I didn't put.
But once I kind of got the idea
of what this font thing was
all about and recreated that,
I was good to go.
Or once I sort of felt
like I got close enough
with these visuals and learned the lessons
I was gonna learn, I was good to go.
So technically, I say, yeah,
recreate this pixel-for-pixel.
But really the idea is,
you're here to learn lessons
from the original design,
so you don't necessarily
wanna overthink it,
you don't really wanna under-think it.
You just wanna get to the point
where you feel like you're learning
and you're taking away
tactics for your own designs.
So I'm actually just gonna really quickly
show you what this looks like.
Here's OpenAI.com.
And this is a site where
I think they redesigned pretty recently.
They've always had a nice site.
But when I land here, they've
got this crazy color thing
goin' on in the background
and they also have a really nice font.
I can go look at this.
Okay, it's Colfax AI, so it's
probably just the Colfax font.
But there's some cool stuff,
mostly with this colored
background that's goin' on here.
And I might wanna do some copywork
to see if I can kind
of learn how to do this
and incorporate it into my
own set of designer tricks.
So I'm just gonna go ahead
and take a screenshot here.
I'm pressing shift control,
command four on the Mac,
which is gonna allow me to click and drag,
grab a screenshot, we'll
paste it in right here.
Whoop, there we go.
And I'm gonna press A
to create a new frame.
I'm just gonna do probably
a slightly smaller one,
so I can actually see everything.
Make that a little bit
smaller, this'll be here.
Okay, cool.
And I'll have these two
things side by side.
And really, I don't
necessarily want to trace.
I don't wanna like necessarily
put this onto the art board
and then recreate each element
exactly pixel-for-pixel.
I kinda wanna eyeball things at first
just because I'm gonna
learn more that way,
trying to get it about right.
But there's really no rule against
going and double-checking here.
So with this color stuff,
one thing I wanna do
is go and look at how it's going on.
And this is not required.
I could just kinda try
and do this in Figma,
but I actually, I do code a little bit
and I kinda wanna see how
they're making this work.
It looks like they've got
a bunch of rectangles,
and all these rectangles are
maybe kind of blurry colors.
Cool.
Then I end up with just
this page at the bottom.
So I can slowly undo this
and kinda see how it builds
up from the beginning.
I'm gonna start.
I've got kinda this dark
blue, almost indigo color.
Now, I recognize for a beginner,
you're not necessarily going to be able to
eyeball these colors at first glance
and be able to get them looking great.
That's okay.
You're gonna get much better
at it in the color unit.
And then I'll make this a
gradient instead, perfect.
Zero to 100% opacity and
then kind of rotate it a bit.
And my goal is not to
get this exactly correct.
I just kinda wanna get the
general gist of things.
I'm showing you a realistic example.
I found this today and I was
like, wow, that looks cool.
I actually want to try and do that.
I don't necessarily expect
that you're going to be doing
the same sort of thing here.
Just, this is actually
kind of a tough example.
This is a really cool site
and I feel like it's sort
of a modern technique.
A lot of the copywork, which we'll get to
in just a sec here,
boils down to things like
kind of choosing similar
fonts that look good
or just overall choosing the
right set of theme colors.
Maybe you do some recreation of icons,
and that's where you learn
some of those techniques
that end up being so
useful again and again.
Now I'm gonna write Open
AI in the upper left.
One of the tougher parts of doing copywork
is you don't always get access
to the fonts even on the Web.
So, in this case, Open
AI is written in white,
but it is, you know, I
don't know what font that is
and it might actually be somethin' custom.
So it's kinda up to me
to use my best judgment.
I have listed below some
resources that you can go to
to try and match fonts,
and figure out what font
you're actually looking at.
It's gonna be tough, no
matter which way I slice it.
But, to me, the important part
is not that I get this exactly right.
I'm gonna actually just
kinda pick somethin'
I know there's a, Input Mono
is one that's sort of similar.
Input Sans is actually really close, too,
so I might try that one.
And then, to me, this also looks
like IBM's font, Plex Mano.
And I think there's a Plex Sans, too.
And so I might just say,
which is the one that kind
of has that character,
this character, the most?
Maybe it would be like this
with a little bit less
letter spacing or something.
I'm not gonna overthink it.
I'm just tryin' to get somethin'
that like generally works,
and that's all I'm really going for.
The sizing is important.
I want the size to feel about the same,
so maybe I'll just shrink
this by like a point or two,
and then I'll see if
there's a medium weight.
Does that look better?
And then we have API
Projects Blog and About.
These are gonna go into
the top right corner.
So I'll press T to make a new text box.
And one thing I can do in
Figma is select all these
and press shift A.
That's gonna make an auto layout,
and I'm gonna have some control over
exactly what the
horizontal spacing is here.
These are all upper case,
so if I press enter,
it's gonna select all
four layers independently.
And in the "Setting Up
Your Workspace" video,
I show you how you can use a hot key
to create everything uppercase.
So if I just press command shift U,
all of this becomes upper case.
I'm gonna definitely wanna
have all of these be smaller,
maybe 14 works well.
And then I'm also gonna wanna
letter space 'em a little bit.
Now, Colfax is not actually a free font.
That's a paid font, and
it cost hundreds of bucks
and I don't own it, and
I'm not gonna get it
just for this exercise.
So one thing that I do is
I have Typewolf's Guide to Free Fonts,
which is a paid resource.
If you're gonna use it a lot,
it's probably worth getting.
I think it's like 40 bucks or so.
But he has in here, I think
over 1,000 paid fonts.
And then what are the closest free fonts?
So Cooper Hewitt or Roboto.
In this case, let's just use Roboto here.
It makes it look like I need to put in
just a bit more letter spacing here,
and I'll put this stuff up
in the upper right here.
So now I'll just make it
40 pixels from the edge.
This'll be 40 pixels from the other edge.
I don't know if that's exactly
right, it's close enough.
So there we go, that looks about right.
Maybe there's a little more
line spacing in the original.
It's not necessarily what I'm here for.
So again, I'm not gonna
worry too much about it.
But if I was a beginner, I
would be takin' notes here.
And then I can go grab
this text right here.
It looks like it's smaller,
let's say like size 18 or somethin'.
Just paste it in there.
Auto line height, no, needs
to be a little bit more.
Should be close enough.
And then we have Explore
Our API and Learn More.
So I just need to do
those buttons real quick.
I think what's going on here
is they have a little black rectangle
that has a pretty low opacity.
So throw that on here,
give it a 10% opacity,
that looks like it could be right.
And it has a border radius C four.
You know, one thing you can do,
especially if you're familiar
with the Developer Console,
is it's not like it's against the rules
to go look at this sort of stuff.
But I usually like to
try and give things a go
before I go look at exactly, say,
if I can find the border radius here.
I don't even know where
it is, four pixels, yeah.
So my guess happened to be correct.
So you can always reference that
if you know how to read that stuff
and you wanna get things
looking exactly correct.
But again, the goal is learning.
So it's like, is that cheating
or is it not cheating?
It doesn't really matter.
It's just about how are
you learning the most?
So this one says Explore Our API.
But it actually looks like
it more or less says it
with that font style,
so I'm gonna copy and paste
the existing font style.
And that just helps
keep things consistent.
Now, I can again make an auto layout.
Figma thinks that I actually
want this to be 100% fill,
which I don't, but this
allows me to really quickly
go and make these, let's
see, how's that look?
Pretty similar.
Now, they also have this little icon here.
Chances are, that's not a text character.
That's an icon that they've added.
It's up to me if I wanna
try and add this in.
I'm actually probably
just gonna skip it for now
because it would be
significantly more work,
and I don't really need to
learn about icons right now.
But if I was just getting started,
I would totally recreate
that icon as well.
And we'll talk about
this in the icon lesson,
but there's all kinds
of things to learn about
how to craft good icons.
And one that I see them doing is,
you'll notice a good icon is often
about the same stroke width
as the text that it's next to,
so it kind of blends in.
This icon technically
feels a little bit smaller,
maybe a little bit thinner,
but overall, it's like pretty similar.
All right.
And there we go.
I feel like that's not perfect.
There's maybe some
things I would change up.
I could have put more time
into trying to get the
colors exactly right.
But one of the funny things
about Open AI and the site
is every time you refresh the page,
the colors look different.
So it's kinda like this technique
where they're generating
this stuff in the background
and they're using some
rules for how to do it.
So it's not necessarily super-important
that I get this exactly right.
But if I am trying to
use something like this
in my own design, I wanna
have a general sense
of how it's done, which I learned,
oh, I can just do these rectangles,
these just big, randomly
positioned rectangles
with bright radial gradients
that are yellow, purple and blue,
and it kinda makes this
awesome hodgepodge of colors.
And then if I'm developing the site,
I have that technique in
sort of my bag of tricks.
Not that I'd wanna copy
it exactly on a site,
but I could use that sort
of idea at some other point.
And if I'm working with a developer
who's gonna implement the site,
then I can tell them
about how to do this, too,
and we can sort of experiment
and create an awesome design.
And to me, this is super cool.
I have been designing for years
and I had never actually known
how to recreate this effect
until I just opened this
up today and did it.
So it's very possible,
even at higher skill levels
to learn tons of stuff from copywork.
It's really a great exercise.
And again, I kind of tried
to narrate some of the things
that I'd be thinking about
if I was just starting out,
you know, maybe you do
more of the icon work
and focus more on the typography,
the alignment, the spacing.
Just absorbing those
little lessons about layout
is gonna be super, super helpful.
There we go, let's get that stuff aligned.
Can't talk about alignment
and not do it myself.
And then the neat thing is,
once you see this pop up in one place,
you'll see it pop up everywhere.
Like, for instance, I
just thought of this,
literally this Stripe Climate
site that I saw yesterday,
they have this bar where it's kinda like
morphing between these gradients
and it's a similar effect.
I haven't actually looked and
seen how they're doing this.
They have kind of added
an animation on top,
it's not just a still image.
But the idea is, once I
have some sort of idea
of how to do this, I can twist it,
put my own little take on it,
and then use it in different places.
So that's super-cool.
That is the power of copywork.
Okay, so copywork is
fantastic for inspiration
where you just kind of
generally wanna learn
some random lessons from it.
And we've seen that.
But a lot of inspiration you might find
for a specific project.
And so what do you do
with that if not copywork?
Well, you might compile
what the industry refers
to as a mood board.
And a mood board is just
sort of a number of shots.
They can be, let's say
these are all pieces of UI,
but they're all for a specific project.
And so this is some stuff that I gathered
for a project that I did for
Philo, and Philo is a TV site.
Well, as a TV site, we're
gonna talk about this
in the imagery lesson,
but when you have awesome
imagery at your fingertips,
you need to use it to create a good UI.
It's gonna make a world of difference
in making a UI look
really clean and awesome.
And so when you have something
like all this artwork
from different TV shows, or in this case,
I have collected inspiration
from different movie sites,
here's all this movie stuff.
All of these sites look
really, really cool.
And I might analyze any
of them and figure out
some little trick or way to
use an image of something on TV
and make the Philo site
look really, really awesome.
So not only is this other sites
that are doing similar things
and kind of have the same brand
that you've identified
that you wanna have,
but you could also put in sites
that are kind of in adjacent industries,
or maybe like do something well,
and even if it's not
exactly what you're doing,
you still might learn from it.
So let me give a concrete example
that this is a music site.
Like, these are just albums, right?
That's not the same thing as TV shows.
And TV shows wouldn't even
necessarily have these
little square displays like album covers.
And you might not see so many
on just one screen like this.
But there's interesting ideas here.
I like how it's laid out.
I like the simplicity of the information.
The sidebars might be
something that I could borrow.
I don't know where this
blurred-out background came from,
but there's an idea that maybe I could use
for something related to TV.
So a mood board is just this
collection of inspiration
that's applicable to
one particular project.
It's similar brands, it's
things that are doing
the same problems, that are
solving the same problems well,
even if they're different industries.
Sometimes you might put
competitors on here,
but I sort of hesitate.
Design is a really great
way to distinguish yourself
from your competitors.
So you don't wanna soak them up too much
as inspiration necessarily.
You can also use Dribbble collections
as a way of sort of
assembling mood boards.
So let's see if I can remember
any that I had done for this.
It's tough to remember, but
I believe Video Game Style
was something that I had this for.
Oh, the one with code.
This was, I was working on
a code editor at one point
and so I wanted to collect all these.
And so it was like kind of a
baked into Dribbble mood board
with a bunch of code editors.
Now, mood boards can also
be a little abstract.
They don't necessarily need to be just UI.
So another project that
I worked on was Alexa,
the Amazon Echo.
And some of the designers
that I was working with
were responsible for the light design.
You know, when you talk
to it, it lights up.
What is that light gonna look like?
And these are questions that
people have thought long and hard about.
But at one point, I walked
into my boss's office
and he had all of these
sort of mood board images
of just different lights.
And you can see this isn't a,
none of these are UI, right?
These are a little bit more abstract,
but they kind of represent the feel
of what lights could be like.
Lights can mean kind of
like, hey, let's party.
Lights can be like majestic and beautiful.
Lights can be warm and comforting.
Lights can be mechanical and
sort of powerful and wild.
And they can be all these
other, I don't know,
symbols and different things like that.
So just kind of thinking like,
what are the connotations
of different types of lights
can help you with any
sort of design problem,
even if it's not necessarily digital.
So I think mood boards that
you assemble for UI projects
are typically gonna
lean more towards this.
But anything that kind of
is getting across the vibe
or the brand that you're going for,
that's the sort of stuff you
can throw on a mood board.
And these are the things
you'd reference throughout
the rest of the project,
just to kinda say, am I on track?
Am I drawing inspiration
from the things I want
and hitting the brand that I want to hit?
Now, this whole lesson
has been about copying basically, right?
Like you're looking at design inspiration.
In some cases, you are
copying it pixel-for-pixel
as an exercise.
And so I just wanna take a second
and sort of address the
elephant in the room,
which is plagiarism.
You don't want to be plagiarizing
other people's designs,
but you do wanna be inspired
by the best of what's out there.
So there's a couple things you
can do to avoid plagiarism.
Certainly, one idea is,
if you draw inspiration
from multiple sources,
then it's less plagiarism
and more just recombination.
So if I go and get, say, like
a font from a particular site
that I like, I might use that font.
I wouldn't use the colors
from that same site.
I might draw inspiration
for a similar set of colors
from a different site.
And for the imagery, maybe I have,
my inspiration is yet a third site,
that I end up using some sort of motif
or do somethin' similar to what they do.
But another fantastic way
to avoid sort of advertently
or inadvertently copying off of someone
is to, when you do any sort
of inspiration-gathering,
do it one day where you
find your inspiration
and you analyze it, but
then step two, sleep on it.
And step three, do your design work
without looking at the original.
So what's kind of coming out
is the lessons that you
remember from there,
but you're still sort of
doing things in your own way.
So that can be another good
way to avoid inadvertently
sort of plagiarizing
or getting too similar
to one piece of design.
But in general, the more things
that you can draw inspiration from,
and the more time you
can put in between, say,
copywork and analysis, and
then designing, the better;
the better off you're gonna be
in terms of not ripping off
of someone else's designs.
So, folks, that wraps it up.
Thanks for watchin'.
For homework today, I'm kinda
throwing you in the deep end.
You've got a bunch of stuff to do,
including copywork and mood boards.
But these are really cool assignments,
and students have historically
liked them quite a bit.
So take a look, do it.
I hope you learn tons.
When you're done, post it
in the Student Community,
and we'll see you in the next lesson.